Token is a fancy term for a symbol.
“词条 (token)” 是“符号”的高级表达
Usually, one that holds some meaning and is not typically split up any further.
一般指具有某种意义 无法再分拆的符号
In case of natural language processing,
在自然语言处理中
our tokens are usually individual words.
词条通常是单独的词
So tokenization is simply splitting each sentence into a sequence of words.
因此 分词 (tokenization) 就是将每个句子分拆成一系列词
The simplest way to do this is using the split method which returns a list of words.
最简单的方法是使用 split 方法 返回词列表
Note that it splits on whitespace characters by default,
请注意 默认情况下在空格字符处分拆
which includes regular spaces but also tabs,
包括普通空格 标签
new lines, et cetera.
新行等
It's also smart about ignoring two or more whitespace characters in a sequence,
这种方法还很智能 能够忽略一个序列中的两个或多个连续空格字符
so it doesn't return blank strings.
因此不会返回空字符串
But you can control all this using optional parameters.
但是 你可以使用可选参数对它进行控制
So far, we've only been using Python's built-in functionality,
目前为止 我们只使用了 Python 的内置功能
but some of these operations are much easier to perform using a library like NLTK,
但是使用诸如NLTK库 这样的一些操作就会简单许多
which stands for natural language toolkit.
NLTK 也就是“自然语言工具包”的意思
The most common approach for splitting up texting NLTK is to
在 NLTK 中分拆文本的最常见方法是
use the word tokenized function from nltk.tokenize.
使用 nltk.tokenize 中的 word tokenize 函数
This performs the same task as split but is a little smarter.
这与 split 的功能相同 但稍微智能一些
Try passing in some raw text that has not been normalized.
在尝试传入未标准化的原始文本时
You'll notice that the punctuations are treated differently based on their position.
你会发现 根据标点符号位置的不同 对它们的处理也不同
Here, the period after the title Doctor has
头衔 Dr 后面的点号
been retained along with Dr as a single token.
与 Dr 保留在一起 作为一个词条
As you can imagine,
可想而知
NLTK is using some rules or patterns to decide what to do with each punctuation.
NLTK 使用某种规则或模式决定如何处理每个标点符号
Sometimes, you may need to split text into sentences.
比如 如果你想翻译文本
For instance, if you want to translate it.
可能需要将文本分拆成句子
You can achieve this with NLTK using sent tokenize.
可以通过 NLTK 使用 sent tokenize 来实现这一点
Then you can split each sentence into words if needed.
然后可以根据需要将每个句子分拆成词
NLTK provide several other tokenizers,
NLTK 提供多种分词器
including a regular expression base tokenizer that you can use to
包括基于正则表达式的分词器
remove punctuation and perform tokenization in a single step,
可以只需一步 即可清除标点符号并将其分词
and also a tweet tokenizer that is aware of twitter handles,
还包括推文分词器 它能识别 twitter 句柄
hash tags, and emoticons.
话题标签和表情符号
Check out the nltk.tokenize package for more details.
查看 nltk.tokenize 包 了解更多详细信息